Allan Marquand Papers, 1858-1951 (bulk 1878-1950): Finding Aid C0269
Manuscripts Division
Allan Marquand Papers
1858-1951
1878-1950
Manuscripts Division
Princeton University. Library. Special Collections
Marquand, Allan, 1853-1924.
C0269
54 boxes
27.2 linear feet
Consists of the papers of Allan Marquand, Princeton art professor, founder of the University's Department of Art and Archaeology, and first director of its Art Museum.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains the personal papers of Allan Marquand--including manuscripts, correspondence, photographs, miscellaneous material, and printed matter--reflecting his career in the art world, especially as an expert and cataloguer of the works of the Robbia family. Included are manuscripts for Decoration of the Ceppo Hospital at Pistoia (1902), Della Robbias in America (1912), "Some Works by Donatello in America" (1913), and Strzygowski and His Theory of Early Christian Art (1910). There is also material dating from his earlier years as a student when his interests were in the field of theology and philosophy, specifically, logic.
The papers as a whole contain material for historians of Princetoniana, for there is material both direct and tangential which deals with the life of Marquand the student, founder of the Department of Art and Archaeology, chairman of the department, director of the art museum, and founder of the library that was later named for him. Related material includes the manuscript for "Painting by Hieronymus Bosch in the Princeton Art Museum." Marquand's interests extended into the greater Princeton community, and the collection chronicles the history of the Princeton Battle Monument, culminating in its dedication in 1922.
Included in the collection are the papers of Eleanor Cross Marquand, wife of Allan Marquand and an authority in her own right on the identification of plant symbolism in art. Many of the notes, manuscripts, photographs, and slides she used for her articles and speeches can be found here. There are also papers of Marquand's father, Henry Gurdon Marquand, one of the founders and original benefactors of the Metropolitan Museum of Art.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Given by Mrs. Douglas Delanoy, daughter of Allan Marquand, over a period of time, from 1952 to 1980.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Appraisal
No appraisal information is available.
Marquand, Allan, 1853-1924.
Biographical / Historical
Allan Marquand was born on December 10, 1853, the son of Henry Gurdon Marquand, a prominent New York banker who was an original benefactor and co-founder of the Metropolitan Museum of Art. Marquand became the salutatorian and president of the Princeton Class of 1874, and studied theology at the Princeton Theological Seminary for three years following graduation. He later received a Ph.D. in philosophy from Johns Hopkins University. During his time at Johns Hopkins, Marquand studied logic and was introduced to "logical machines," mechanical devices built to follow logical algorithms which are often considered precursors to modern computers. He constructed his own logic machine, on display in Fine Hall library, during his early years as a professor at Princeton.
As a professor at Princeton, Marquand founded Princeton's Department of Art and Archaeology. He shares with Charles Eliot Norton of Harvard the distinction of being the first to introduce the serious study of art into the curriculum of the American college. Marquand also became the first director of the Princeton Art Museum and made numerous important gifts to its collection. His own life work was an eight-volume catalogue raisonné of the works of the ateliers of members of the Robbia family, 15th- and 16th-century Florentine sculptors and ceramists.
Ceramic sculpture--Italy--Florence.; Logic machines--United States--19th century.; Princeton Battle Monument (N.J.); Sculptors--Italy--Florence--15th century.; Symbolism in flowers.; Correspondence.; Manuscripts.; Notebooks.; Art historians--United States.; College of New Jersey (Princeton, N.J.). Class of 1874.; Metropolitan museum of art New York, N.Y.; Princeton university art museum; Princeton university. Department of art and archaeology; Bosch, Hieronymus, -1516; Marquand, Eleanor Cross, 1873-1950; Strzygowski, Josef, 1862-1941
- Series 1: Writings, 1872-1926; 10 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access
  The collection is open for research.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains notebooks from Marquand's undergraduate days at Princeton through drafts of his published manuscripts.
  Arrangement
  Organized into three subseries relating to Marquand's major interests: Philosophy (and Logic), Theology, and Art.
  - Subseries 1A: Philosophy, 1872-1881; 3 boxes
    Consists of the writings of Allan Marquand pertaining to Philosophy, including "An Analysis of Book I, Parts I, II, and III of McCosh's Intuitions and Other Subjects Relating to Mental Science," "Philodemus on Inductive Signs and Inferences," and "Utilitarianism in Morals-- An Analysis," as well as others.
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Achilles and Tortoise, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "An Analysis of Book I, Parts I, II, & III of McCosh's Intuitions and Other Subjects Relating to Mental Science", 1873; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "The Development Hypothesis by Calidore", 1874; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Examinations, 1879; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Experiments in Probability and Notes onTransitiveness, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "The General Form of the Copula", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Ideal Philosophers", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 7)
      The Republic, Book VI
    - Kant, 1877-1878; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Berlin
    - "A Large Number of Repetitions of Similar Trends", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 9)
      in the hand of Charles S. Pierce
    - Logic, 1878-1879; 2 folders (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
    - Logic, 1879-1881; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Logic, 1881; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Logic, undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Logic, undated; 5 folders (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
    - "Logic in Middle Ages", 1879-1880; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - "On the Word 'Copula' in Logic", 1879 May; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Personal Relations, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Philodemus, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "Philodemus on Inductive Signs and Inferences", 1880; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 10)
      part of thesis for Ph.D., Johns Hopkins
    - Philosophy Class Notes, Psychology Reading Notes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Philosophy Lecture, 1878 October; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
      at Johns Hopkins
    - "Physiology of Sensation", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Psychology, 1872; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - "A Sketch of the Ethics of the Epicureans", 1875 December; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
      written for Dr. McCosh's Library Meeting
    - "A Study of German Social Democracy", 1878; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "Utilitarianism in Morals-- An Analysis", 1874 September; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous: Bibliography of French and German Books, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous: W. W. I Military Course, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 1B: Theology, 1874-1878; 1 box
    Consists of the writings of Allan Marquand pertaining to Theology, including "But Jesus Did Not Commit Himself Unto Them Because He Knew All Men," "Latin Thesis: Quo Modo Intercedit Christus?," and "Speaking the Truth in Love," as well as others.
    - "And Terah Died in Haran", 1876; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 1)
      essay on Genesis 11:32
    - "But Jesus Did Not Commit Himself Unto Them Because He Knew All Men", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 2)
      religious tract
    - Church History, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Courses Taught by Hitchcock & Shedd, 1876; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - General Introduction to Old Testament Taught by Dr. Green, 1874; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - "Immeusee", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Translating from the German of Theodor Storm, Marquand wrote it "To my sisters Mabel & Bessie".
    - "Influence of Geographical Position on Idea of Future World", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 7)
      essay
    - "Intelligent Faith", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 8)
      essay on John 1:39
    - "Latin Thesis: Quo Modo Intercedit Christus?", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Lecture, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 10)
      on Isaiah 61:1-3 (Dr. Hall)
    - "Nature's Testimony to the Immortality of the Soul", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 11)
      speech
    - Outside Reading, 1875; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Professor McGill's Course on "Church Government" at Princeton Theological Seminary, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Religious Courses, 1876; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 14)
      Briggs--Biblical Theology; Hitchcock--Church History; Dr. Adams
    - "The Reasonableness of Consecrating Ourselves to Christ", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 15)
      sermon on Romans 12:1
    - "The Soul's Rest in God", 1878; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 16)
      on Psalms 46:1, Berlin
    - "Speaking the Truth in Love", 1878; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 17)
      on Ephesians 4:15, Berlin
  - Subseries 1C: Art, 1874-1926; 6 boxes
    Consists of the writings of Allan Marquand pertaining to Art, including "An Altarpiece at Montefiascone," "A Lunette of S. Lorenzo and Angels by Benedetto da Majano, 1496," and "The Old Olympic Games," as well as others.
    Arranged by genre of material.
    - Notebooks, 1883; 1 box
      - Architecture and Psychology, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Benedetto Buglioni, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Egyptian Studies (including sketches), 1883; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Greek Art, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Greek Mythology, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Italy (notes and drawings), 1883 April-May; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous Notes on Art History, etc., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Sketch Book, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Strzygowski and Others, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 10)
        art history, as well as chemistry
    - Della Robbias: Published Manuscripts and Pictures, Notes, and Miscellaneous Material, 1902-1922; 2 boxes
      - "Andrea della Robbia", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - "Andrea della Robbia and His Atelier", 1922; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 2)
        Princeton Monographs in Art and Archaeology
      - "Boy with a Dolphin by Andrea della Robbia", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Della Robbias, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
        Pictures I and II
      - Della Robbias in America, 1912; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - "A Kneeling Madonna by Giovanni della Robbia", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - "Luca and Andrea della Robbia and Their Successors by Maud Crutwell", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 8)
        book review
      - "Luca della Robbia", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - "Luca della Robbia", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 10)
        Art and Archaeology
      - "Notes on the della Robbia in Lisbon", 1915; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - "On Some Recently Discovered Works by Luca della Robbia", 1912; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 12)
        Journal of the Archaeological Institute of America, Vol. XVI, no. 2, pp. 163-174
      - "Robbia Pavements", 1902; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 13)
        The Brickbuilder, pp. 55-57, 98-101
      - "A Statuette of Dovizia by Giovanni della Robbia in the Minneapolis Museum", 1917; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 14)
        Art in America, pp. 195-199, typed and handwritten drafts
      - "The Visitation at Pistoia by Luca della Robbia", 1914 July; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 15)
        Version I, Art and Archaeology, Vol. I, no. 1, pp. 21-26
      - "The Visitation by Luca della Robbia at Pistoia", 1907; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 16)
        Version II, Journal of the Archaeological Institute of America, Vol. XI, No. 1, pp. 36-41
      - "The Works of the della Robbias", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Della Robbia Studies, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
        notebooks, including "Visitation at Pistoia" and "Santi Buglioni"
      - Notes on the della Robbia School, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
      - Notes on the della Robbias, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Unpublished Documents Relating to the Will of Andrea della Robbia, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous della Robbia Material, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
    - Other Published Manuscripts and Speeches, 1889 October-1926; 1 box
      - "An Altarpiece at Montefiascone", 1923; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 1)
        Art Review
      - "Antonio Rossellino's Madonna of the Candelabra", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 2)
        Art in America
      - "Arms of the Ginovi Family", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 3)
        Art in America, pp. 242-246
      - "The Barney Madonna with Adoring Angels", 1925-1926; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 4)
        Art Studies, Vol. II
      - "The Decoration of the Ceppo Hospital at Pistoia", 1902; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 5)
        Brickbuilder Monthly, Vol. 11, No. 11, pp. 222-224
      - "The Dome of Saint Sergius at Constantinople", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 6)
        Records of the Past, Vol. V, part XII, pp. 355-362
      - "Donatello", 1894 June; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 7)
        The Princeton College Bulletin, Vol. VI, No. 3, pp. 66-67
      - "Equestrian Statue of Bartolomeneo Colleoni", 1919-1920; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 8)
        Art and Life
      - "The Form of the Princeton Battle Monument"; "The History of the Princeton Battle Monument", 1919; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - A History of European and American Sculpture from the Early Christian Period to the Present Day by Chandler R. Post Book review, 1922 April 22; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 10)
        from the New York Evening Post
      - "A Lunette of S. Lorenzo and Angels by Benedetto da Majano, 1496", 1922; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - "The Martelli David and the Youthful St. John Baptist", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 12)
        Art in America, pp. 358-366
      - "Mino da Fiesole", 1920 May; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - "A New Document for the Ceppo Hospital Medallion", 1920; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 14)
        American Journal of Archaeology, Second Series, Vol. XXIV, No. 3, pp. 269-270
      - "The Old Olympic Games", 1896; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 15)
        Century Magazine
      - "On the Significance of the Words Sculpture, Sculptor, and Statuary", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 16)
        Prepared by request of the General Board of Appraisers
      - "The Orange and the Blue", 1895 November; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 17)
        Princeton College Bulletin, Vol. VIII, No. 1
      - "A Painting by Hieronymus Bosch in the Princeton Art Museum", 1903 March; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 18)
        Princeton University Bulletin, Vol. XIV, No. II, pp. 41-47
      - "The Papal Tiara and a Relief in the Princeton Museum", 1914; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 19)
        Art in America, pp. 153-158
      - "A Phoenician Bowl in the Metropolitan Museum", 1891; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 20)
        American Journal of Archaeology, Vol. XII (1892) Nos. 1-2, pp. 1-6
      - "The Princeton Colors", 1917 December; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 21)
        Letter to the Editor of the Princetonian
      - "Princeton University", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 22)
        Princeton College Bulletin, Vol. VII, No. 4, pp. 1-7
      - Raffaello by Adolfo Venturi Book review, 1920; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - "Remarks on the Study of Architecture at Princeton" (at Dedication of McCormick Hall), 1923 June 16; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 24)
        Dedication of McCormick Hall, pp. 14-24
      - "Reminiscences of Egypt in Doric Architecture", 1889 October; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 25)
        American Journal of Archaeology, Vol. 6, No. 1, 12 pages, American Oriental Society's Proceedings
      - "The Rockefeller Venus", 1917 May; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 26)
        Art and Archaeology, pp. 299-302
      - "Some Works of Donatello in America", 1913 October; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 27)
        Art in America, Vol. I, No. IV, October 1913, pp. 211-225
      - "Stryzgowski and His Theory of Early Christian Art", 1910 July; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 28)
        Harvard Theological Review, Vol. III, pp. 357-365
      - Studien über Leonardo da Vinci by Wilhem von Bode Book review, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - "A Terracotta Bust of Francois I", 1913 January; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 30)
        Art in America, Vol. I, No. 1, pp. 39-47
      - "The Tomb of Ilaria del Carretto", 1915; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 31)
        American Journal of Archaeology, Second Series, Vol. XIX, No. 1, pp. 24-33
      - "Two Busts of Houdon in the collection of Henry C. Frick", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 32)
        Art in America, pp. 65-72
      - "Two Works of Venetian Sculpture", 1917; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 33)
        Art in America, pp. 56-60
      - "A Venetian Doorway by Pietro Lombardo", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 34)
        Art in America, pp. 142-146
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1874-1922 August 13; 1 box
      - "Bossuet Comparé avec Fénelon", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - "The College Buildings", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - "The Comet of 1910", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 3)
        a poem for Dean West
      - "Early Christian Iconography"; "A School of Ivory Carvers in Provence", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - "Ghiberti and the Baptistery Gates", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - "The History of Art as a University Study" and other texts, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 6)
        including: 2 ALsS to Archeological Society of America/New York Society; 1 AMs "On College Students who are not Candidates for a degree"; 1 AMs, unidentified
      - "Howard Crosby Butler", 1922 August 13; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - "Impressions of Yucatan", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 8)
        including comments on the architecture
      - "Italian Painting", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - "Origins of Painting in Italy", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - "New Professorship for the Department of Art & Archaeology", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Notes on Signorelli's Dante Illustrations, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - "Salutatory", 1874; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 13)
        given at Princeton University
    - Drafts, Notes, Fragments, 1891; 1 box
      - "Archaeology of Rome and other parts of Italy, Crete and Greece" by Giov. Marcanova, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - "Bust of Sarapis", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 2)
        from King Collection, Metropolitan Museum
      - "Contemporary American Sculptors", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Draft on Appointment of Graduate Scholarships, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Egyptian Chronology, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 5)
        recovery of the Lost Calendar
      - Fragments of Notes on Art History & Related Subjects, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - "Gems from the King Collection in the Metropolitan Museum of Art" in New York City, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - "Head of Claudius", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Incomplete Notes on Works Attributed to Donatello, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 9)
        in America
      - Miscellaneous & Unidentified Fragments of Notes Relating to History of Art, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous Notes, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 10, Folder 11-12)
      - "Morgan Collection of Greek Jewelry", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 13)
        in Metropolitan Museum
      - "Note on Brunelleschi's Sacrifice of Isaac", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Notes on Architecture, Sculpture and Printing, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Notes on Art History, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Note on Christian Art, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Notes on Greek Mask Discovered at Alba, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Notes on Hellenistic Studies, 1891; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - Notes on Sculpture, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - Notebook on the Architecture of Egypt and Assyria, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - "On Scientific Method in the Study of Art", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - "On the Question as to What Pictures Are Entitled to Be Called Ancient or Old Masters", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - "Renaissance Architecture as an Index of Social Progress", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - "Renaissance Sculpture", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 25)
      - "Resurrection (stained glass window) by Ghiberti", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 26)
        at Florence Cathedral Cupola
      - "Romanesque Inscriptions", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 27)
      - "A Unique Bridal Wreath" (Corona Nuptials), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 28)
      - "University Exterior Lectures on the History of Art", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 29)
      - "A Venetian Portal", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 30)
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1872-1924; 1950-1951; 9 boxes
  The series contains correspondence from friends, colleagues, and organizations, representative of Marquand's wide range of contacts in the art world. The correspondence dates from his undergraduate years up to the year of his death.
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - A. J. Crawford Co, 1910; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Adam, William L., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Adams, Charles Kendall (1835-1902), 1886 March 4; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Adams, Dr, 1878; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Adams, W, 1877; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Alexander, Charles B, 1872-1873; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Alexander, Stephen (1806-1883), 1876; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Allbutt, Sir Clifford (1836-1925), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Allen, Arthur M. Class of 1872?, 1875; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Allinson, F. G. (1856-1931), 1880; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Alma-Tadema, Sir Lawrence (1836-1912), 1882-1904; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - American Academy in Rome, 1920-1922; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 12)